Guide to the Elizabeth Robins Papers 1803-1963 MSS 002
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: General Correspondence
  - Subseries B: General Correspondence, 1888-1952
    - Richmond, Lady Elsa (Bell)1893-1949, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 151)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 1, Folder 5; Series V: Florence Bell, Subseries D.
    - Ritchie, Anne Thackeray 1896, 1918, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 152)
    - Rothenstein, Sir William 1919-1940, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 153)
    - "S" 1888-1938 (Box 21, Folder 154)
    - "S" 1940-1949, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 155)
    - Schreiner, Olive 1914-1915 (Box 21, Folder 156)
    - Scott, David 1908 (Box 22, Folder 157)
      ER to DS. See also Oversize Material, Box 1, Folder 6.
    - Scott, David 1908-1911 (Box 22, Folder 158)
    - Scott, David 1915-1919 (Box 22, Folder 159)
    - Scott, David 1920, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 160)
    - Scott, David 1925-1930 (Box 22, Folder 161)
    - Scott, David 1931-1932 (Box 22, Folder 162)
    - Scott, David 1935,1937-1942, 1935 -1942 (Box 22, Folder 163)
    - Scott, David 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 164)
    - Sharp, Evelyn (Mrs. H.W. Nevinson) 1907-1921 (Box 23, Folder 165)
    - Sharp, Rachel Dyce 1909, 1921-1929, 1909 -1929 (Box 23, Folder 166)
    - Sharp, Rachel Dyce 1930-1933 (Box 23, Folder 167)
    - Sharp, Rachel Dyce 1934 (Box 23, Folder 168)
    - Sharp, Rachel Dyce 1935-1949, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 169)
    - Shaw, Charlotte F. (Mrs. G.B. Shaw) 1904-1927 (Box 23, Folder 170)
    - Shaw, George Bernard 1891-1939, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 171)
      See also correspondence to/from William Archer in Box 7and William T. Stead in Box 24, Folder 179, each includes several letters from ER to GBS.
    - Sherris, Gladys E.M. 1912-1916 (Box 24, Folder 172)
    - Simmonds, Florence (Tarrypin) 1907-1915 (Box 24, Folder 173)
    - Simmonds, Florence (Tarrypin) 1916-1945, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 174)
    - Simons: Hans, Eva 1940-1944, 1946, 1940 -1946 (Box 24, Folder 175)
    - Smith, Sybil (daughter of Louisa, Lady Antrim) 1912-1924, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 176)
    - Spring-Rice, Florence 1915-1916, 1937, n.d., 1915 -1937 (Box 24, Folder 177)
    - St. Albans, Duchess of (Beatrice) 1923, 1937-1940, 1923 -1940 (Box 24, Folder 178)
    - Stead: William T., Estelle 1890-1940, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 179)
      Including postcard from George Bernard Shaw, 5 January 1908.
    - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 0000 (Box 24, Folder *)
      See Box 7, Folder 11: "Archer, William."
    - Stillwell, Elizabeth 1942-1944 (Box 24, Folder 180)
    - Stoker, Bram 1891-1897 (Box 24, Folder 181)
    - Sutro, Alfred 1897-1932, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 182)
    - Symons, Arthur 1893, n.d., 1893 -1893 (Box 24, Folder 183)
    - "T" 1888-1950, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 184)
    - Tadema, Laurence Alma 1897-1900, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 185)
    - Terry: Ellen, Marion 1890-1929, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 186)
    - Tevis, Lloyd 1888-1898, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 187)
      See also Subseries A, Box 4, Folder 56.
    - Thompson, E.A.M. (Mrs. Yates Thompson) 1895-1940, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 188)
    - Thorndike, Dame Sybil 1920-1939, 1946, n.d., 1920 -1946 (Box 25, Folder 189)
    - 190. Tree: Sir Herbert Beerbohm, Maud 1888-1924, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 190)
      See also Series VII, Box 18.
    - Trevelyan: Charles, Molly (Bell), George, Kitty, Pauline 1900-1951, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 191)
    - Twain, Mark 1899 (Box 25, Folder *)
      See Box 10, Folder 42: Samuel Clemens.
    - "V" 1888-1930, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 192)
    - Von Borowsky, Lisa 1925-1951, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 193)
    - "W" 1888-1947 (Box 26, Folder 194)
    - "W" n.d. (Box 26, Folder 195)
    - Walpole, Sir Hugh 1912-1921, 1940, 1912 -1940 (Box 26, Folder 196)
    - Ward: Dorothy, Josephine 1897-1938, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 197)
    - Ward, Mary A. (Mrs. Humphry Ward) 1901-1919, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 198)
    - Waring, Herbert 1892-1893, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 199)
    - Waterford, Beatrix (Mrs. Beatrix Beauclerk) 1917, 1924, 1934, 1917 -1934 (Box 26, Folder 200)
    - Waters, Clara E. Clement (C.E.C.W.) 1895-1913, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 201)
    - Wells, H.G. 1906-1908, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 202)
    - Wells: Thomas B., Harriet ("Pippa") 1912-1918 (Box 27, Folder 203)
    - Wells, Thomas B., Harriet ("Pippa") 1919-1938, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 204)
      See also Series 10, Box 6, Folder 18.
    - West, Rebecca 1919-1920, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 205)
    - Wharton, Edith 1932 (Box 28, Folder 206)
    - Whistler, James McNeil 1891, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 207)
      Includes pencil sketch for Robins' Below the Salt.
    - Wilbur: Dorothea, Earl Morse 1933-1947 (Box 28, Folder 208)
    - Wilde, Oscar 1888-1893, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 209)
    - Wilson, Dr. Philip D. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 210)
    - Wolseley, Viscountess (Frances Garnet) 1921-1934, 1946, n.d., 1921 -1946 (Box 28, Folder 211)
    - Woolf: Virginia, Leonard 1928, 1937-1949, 1928 -1949 (Box 28, Folder 212)
    - Wyndham, Charles 1891, 1892, 1896, 1903, n.d., 1891 -1903 (Box 28, Folder 213)
    - "Y" 1891-1919 (Box 28, Folder 214)
    - Yeats, William Butler 1920 (Box 28, Folder 215)
    - "Z" 1892-1895, 1919, 1929, 1892 -1929 (Box 28, Folder 216)
    - Unidentified letters, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 217)
  - Subseries C: Correspondence by Subject, 1900-1950
    - Aix-les-Bains, 1901 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Alaska, 1900-1901, 1905 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "At Home" Party [Henfield Echoes], 1937 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Backsettown, 1912-1931 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Backsettown, 1932-1948 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Baggage Theft/Damage, 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Boxer Indemnity Commission [effort to find Chinese woman doctor], 1925 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Effort to find a secretary-housekeeper, 1926-1928 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Old Stone House, Zanesville, Ohio and contents, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Scotland Trip, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - "Syllabub" Party [or "At Home at Backsettown Party"], 1934+ (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Time and Tide, 1919-1921 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - USA Trip with Dr. Martindale, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Hot Springs, 1903 (Box 29, Folder 14)
- Series III: Robins Family Papers
  Series III is a collection of papers that enable one to study the close and intricate network of family relationships that formed Elizabeth Robins's earliest environment, and many of them have annotations in Robins's hand. It provides interesting case studies of the family, education (especially of women), religion, and business enterprise in the nineteenth century. The Robins family also served as models for plots and characters in Elizabeth Robins's novels, e.g. The Open Question (published in 1898), "Rocky Mountain Journal", and "Theodora, or The Pilgrimage". There is abundant information, covering a century and a half, on the history of an American family. Raymond Robins's letters can be found in Series IV: Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins.
  Subseries A-G are arranged chronologically. Correspondence with Elizabeth Robins is at the beginning of each subseries, followed by General Correspondence, Business Correspondence and/or personal items such as notebooks, essays, etc. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically; diaries and letterpress books by chronology. The extreme diversity of material in this series complicates uniform arrangement and description.
  - Subseries A: Jane H. Robins, 1814-1885
    Subseries A consists of the papers, mainly correspondence, of Jane Hussey Robins (JHR). JHR was Robin’s paternal grandmother, and appears to have been the dominant female influence on the young Elizabeth Robins; in Robins's words, her "touchstone." Robins would later dedicate an edition of The Open Question to her.
    - Elizabeth Robins (ER) to Jane H. Robins (JHR) 1880, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ER to JHR 1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ER to JHR 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ER to JHR 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ER to JHR 1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ER to JHR 1885 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - JHR to ER 1880-1881, 1889 -1881 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - JHR to ER 1882 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - JHR to ER 1883 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - JHR to ER 1884 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - JHR to ER 1885 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence 1824-1859, 1814 -1859 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      See also Box 43, Folder 1.
    - General Correspondence 1869-1884, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1855-1870 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Robins, Charles E., 0000 (Box 3, Folder *)
      See Box 43, Folder 2 for years 1849-1883.
    - Robins, Charles E. 1871-1872 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1873-1874 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1875 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1876 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1877 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1878 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1879 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1880 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1881 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1882 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1883 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1884 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1885 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Robins: Gurdon - W. Burnet 1833-1878 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Welling family 1877-1885 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - General Business Correspondence 1845-1886 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      See also Box 43, Folder 3.
    - Mackay, J.M. (business), 1845-1854 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      Seee also Box 43, Folder 3 and Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 1.
    - Menzies, J.W. (business) 1848-1865 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      Estate Litigation, 1854-1855. See Box 43, Folders 3 and 4 and Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 1.
    - JHR report cards 1814 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Commonplace book, 1856? (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Extract from various authors, 0000 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Pictorial mementos, 0000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Subseries B: Charles E. Robins, 1836-1893
    Subseries B consists of the papers of Charles Ephraim Robins (1832-1893), and makes up the bulk of Series III. CER was an entrepreneur, a scientist, and politico-religionist. He also wrote and lectured on social issues such as prohibition. CER's papers include extensive business correspondence, which documents his ventures in real estate, insurance, banking, manufacturing, and assaying. In 1875, CER went to the territory of Colorado as an assayer for the Little Annie Gold Mining Company. His office was located at Summit in Rio Grande County, from which he also observed and reported on weather conditions for the United States Army. In 1880 Robins visited him at Summit, just as she would later visit her brothers on the gold fields of Alaska in 1900. CER wrote to his family about the West, religion, God, women's rights, landscapes, the family, and events of the day.
    Subseries B also contains consistent runs of indexed letterpress books (outgoing) and letterbooks (incoming), in addition to 25 volumes of CER's personal diary.
    - Charles E. Robins (CER) to Elizabeth Robins (ER) 1872-1878 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - CER to ER (September-December) 1880 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - CER to ER (April-December) 1881 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Aee also Box 43, Folder 5 for 1881-1891.
    - CER to ER 1882 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - CER to ER (January-June) 1883 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - CER to ER (July-December) 1883 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - CER to ER 1884 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - CER to ER 1885 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - CER to ER 1886 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - CER to ER 1887 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - CER to ER 1888-1889 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - CER to ER 1890 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - CER to ER 1891 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - CER to ER 1892-1893 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - ER to CER 1870?, 1881-1882 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - ER to CER 1883 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ER to CER 1884 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - ER to CER 1885-1893, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence 1846-1860 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - General Correspondence 1861-1891 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Bodine, J.M. 1860-1887 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      See also Box 43, Folder 6.
    - Burnet, Harry 1883-1885 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Dillon family 1853-1886, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Lynd, James Witte 1852-1860 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Hack, Rebecca (Robins) 1839-1886, 1893, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Mack, Samuel E. 1851-1863 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Robins, C.M. 1855-1859 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Robins, Ephraim 1837-1839 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Robins, Eunice (Una) 1883-1885 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Robins, Gurdon 1861-1862 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Robins, Hannah M. (Crow) 1860-1883 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Robins, Henrietta 1847 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Robins, Jane H. 1842-1863 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      See also Box 43, Folder 7 for 1847-1861.
    - Robins, Jane H. 1882-1883 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Robins, Jane H. 1884 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Robins, Jane H. 1885 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Robins, Raymond October 24, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Robins, Sarah E. 1851-1862, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Robins, Saxton 1883-1887, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Robins, Vernon November 24, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Robins, W. Burnet 1836-1885 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Business Correspondence 1849-1856 (Box 11, Folder 42)
      See also Box 43, Folder 8 for 1851-1869.
    - Business Correspondence 1857 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Business Correspondence 1858 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Business Correspondence 1859-1860, 1589 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Business Correspondence 1861 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Business Correspondence 1862 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Business Correspondence 1863 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Business Correspondence 1864-1869 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Business Correspondence 1870-1879 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Business Correspondence 1880-1884 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Business Correspondence 1885-1889 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Little Annie Mining Company Records, 1877-1879 (Box 11, Folder *)
      See Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 2.
    - Alba Light Company Records, 1881-1883 (Box 11, Folder *)
      See Box 43, Folder 9.
    - Business Records, miscellaneous, n.d (Box 11, Folder *)
      See Box 43, Folder 10.
    - October 1853-June 1855, 1853 -1855 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Boxes 12-15 contain letterpress books of letters written by CER. Each "folder" number represents a volume.
    - June 1855-June 1858, 1855 -1858 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - June 1858-July 1861, 1858 -1861 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - February 1863-March 1864, 1863 -1864 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - March 1864-June 1865, 1864 -1865 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - July 1865-December 1866, 1865 -1866 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - January 1867-December 1868, 1867 -1868 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - December 1868-March 1872, 1868 -1872 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - March 1872-October 1876, 1872 -1876 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - November 1875-July 1877, 1875 -1877 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - August 1877-August 1878, 1877 -1878 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - November 1885-January 1890 (extremely fragile), 1885 -1890 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      See also selected TS of books 14 and 15 in Box 28, Folders 53 and 54.
    - December 1863-February 1865, 1863 -1865 (Box 16, Folder A)
      Boxes 16-24 contain letterbooks of letters to CER. Each "folder" is a volume.
    - February 1865-August 1867, 1865 -1867 (Box 17, Folder B)
    - September 1867-August 1868, 1867 -1868 (Box 18, Folder C)
    - June 1868-June 1869, 1868 -1869 (Box 18, Folder D)
    - June 1869-March 1872, 1869 -1872 (Box 19, Folder E)
    - March 1872-April 1873, 1872 -1873 (Box 20, Folder F)
    - May 1875-August 1876, 1875 -1876 (Box 21, Folder G)
    - August 1876-August 1877, 1876 -1877 (Box 21, Folder H)
    - August 1877-April 1878, 1877 -1878 (Box 22, Folder I)
    - April 1878-January 1879, 1878 -1879 (Box 22, Folder J)
    - January 1879-September 1879 (Box 23, Folder K)
    - September 1879-April 1880, 1879 -1880 (Box 23, Folder L)
    - 1881-1883 (Box 24, Folder N)
    - CER diaries (15 volumes) 1857-1873 (Box 25)
      Boxes 25 and 26 hold CER's diaries.
    - CER diaries (10 volumes) 1874-1884 (Box 26)
    - CER business diaries (5 volumes) 1855-1875 (Box 26)
    - CER notebook 1854-1868 (Box 27)
    - CER daybook 1854-1864 (Box 27)
    - CER ledger 1854-1868 (Box 27)
    - Letterpress book selections (TS) from books 14 and 15, 1883-1891 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - Letterpress book selections (TS, carbon) from books 14 and 15 1883-1891 (Box 28, Folder 54)
    - Materials relating to CER's letterpress books, 1883-1891 (Box 28, Folder 54A)
    - Essays by CER (MS, proofs) 1842, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 55)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 3.
    - "With the Nuns" (MS) by CER, ca. 1868 (Box 28, Folder *)
      See Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 3.
    - "The Chronicles of San Juan" speech by CER, 1877 (Box 28, Folder *)
      See Box 43, Folder 11.
    - "Life at Timber Line" by CER (printed) 1879 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - Article on prohibition, by CER (TS) [1888?] (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - Printed Material, undated (Box 28, Folder 58)
    - Unsorted financial records, undated (Box 29)
    - Unsorted financial records, undated (Box 30)
    - Unsorted financial records, undated (Box 31)
    - Unsorted financial records, undated (Box 32)
    - Unsorted financial records, undated (Box 33)
  - Subseries C: Sarah E. Robins, 1838-1866
    Subseries C consists of the papers of Sarah E. Robins (1836-1869), an aunt of Elizabeth Robins. ER felt great kinship with her aunt, Sarah Elizabeth Robins, a poet, and noted on Sarah Robins's correspondence many similarities between their personalities. Sarah Robins appears to have been a role-model for Robins, particularly because of her interests in literature and education. [See the letters of Gorham D. Abbot.] This subseries also contains a letter from Charles Dickens and two letters from Edgar Allan Poe which Sarah Helen Whitman sent to Sarah Robins.
    - General Correspondence 1838-1866 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Abbot, Gorham D. 1862-1863 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Active in movement for women's education.
    - Dickens, Charles June 1, 1861 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Robins family 1849-1869, 1859 -1861 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Whitman, Sarah Helen 1859-1861 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Includes two 1848 Edgar Allan Poe letters.
    - Sarah E. Robins Essays and Poems (MS) 1861, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 6)
      See also Box 40, Folder 7.
    - "Criticism Emancipated" (MS), undated (Box 34, Folder *)
      See Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 4.
    - Commonplace Book (extracts from various authors), also loose pages, undated (Box 34, Folder *)
      See Box 43, Folder 12.
    - Sarah E. Robins Drawings, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Subseries D: Hannah M. Robins, 1841-1890
    Subseries D consists of the papers of Elizabeth Robins’s mother, Hannah Crow Robins (1836-1901). Hannah spent much of her married life with her Crow relations in Louisville, Kentucky, particularly with the Bodines. After the family moved back to Ohio from Staten Island, New York, some of her children were raised in Louisville; Elizabeth Robins usually stayed in Zanesville, Ohio, with her grandmother, Jane Hussey Robins. In 1885, Hannah Robins was committed to an asylum. In addition to correspondence, Subseries D contains Hannah Robins's diary for the year in which Elizabeth Robins was born.
    - Elizabeth Robins (ER) to Hannah M. Robins (HMR) 1872-1884 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - HMR to ER 1880-1882 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - HMR to ER 1883-1885,1887, 1883 -1887 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence 1856-1882, n.d., 1856 -1862 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Bodine Family 1859-1879, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Crow, Mrs. E. K. 1841, 1853-1854, n.d., 1841 -1854 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      See also Box 43, Folder 14.
    - Dillon family 1858-1860, nd (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Fulton, James 1858 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Guthrie, Cornelia (Robins) 1859-1869 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1853, 1860-1864, 1890, 1853 -1890 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Robins, Jane H. 1862 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Robins, Sarah E. 1862 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Stopp, Mr. [letters from H.M. Crow] 1857,1860, 0000 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Hannah M. Crow composition book. n.d., 0000 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Hannah M. Robins diary 1862 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Typescript of portion of HMR's 1862 diary (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Subseries E: Eunice (Una) Robins, 1880-1886
    Subseries E contains the correspondence of Elizabeth’s only sister, Eunice Robins, who died before Robins moved to England.
    - ER to Una Robins 1880-1885, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Una Robins to ER 1880-1886 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Robins: Charles E. and Hannah M. 1885 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Subseries F: Vernon Robins, 1881-1933
    Subseries F consists of the papers of Robins’ brother Vernon. Robins brought her brother Vernon to England to study medicine, and he went on to open a practice in Louisville, Kentucky
    - Vernon Robins (VR) to ER 1881-1899 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - VR to ER 1900-1929 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - VR to ER 1930-1933, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - ER to VR 1887-1894 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - ER to VR (postal cards) 1888-1893, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - ER to VR 1931-1933, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence 1884-1931, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Robins, Charles E. 1888-1891, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Robins, Raymond 1881-1933 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Robins, Saxton 1888-1893, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Personal health records 1887,1889, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Account book 1891 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - School materials 1889, 1890, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material 1889, 1906, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Subseries G: Saxton Robins, 1882-1901
    Subseries G consists of the papers of on Elizabeth Robin’s younger brother, Saxton. Saxton worked for the Alaska Commercial Company in Anvik from about 1897 until his death in 1901. Subseries G contains his Clerk's Record Book, which includes the minutes of several miners meetings.
    - Saxton Robins to ER 1882-1900, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence 1891-1901 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Saxton Robins' Clerk's Record Book, Anvik, Alaska 1899 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Code of Rules for the Citizens of Anvik, Alaska n.d. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Subseries H: Additional Family Members, 1803-1876
    Subseries H contains materials, including letters and notebooks, which belonged to Robins's Hussey, Crow and Robins relations. Notable are the various family genealogies compiled by family members, including Elizabeth Robins, and the family newspaper edited by Rebecca Robins. It also contains two letters, dated 1824 and 1826, to Ephraim Robins from John C. Calhoun.
    - Anonymous--notebook 1831 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Crow, Edward 1826-1840, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - 3. Crow, Elizabeth (Hussey), notebook 1825 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Crow, Elizabeth K. 1846, 1858 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - 5. Hussey, Asabel 1844, 1852, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Hussey, Edith K. 1826, 1834 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - 7. Hussey, Edith K., notebook 1830 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Hussey, Sarah, watercolors book, n.d. (Box 40, Folder *)
      See Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 5.
    - K: "A.S.K." and "A.R."--mathematics notebook 1820 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Mack, Rebecca A. Robins 1855, 1875 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      See also Box 41, Folder 18: Robins, Rebecca and Series II, Subseries A and B.
    - Robins, E. and John N., undated (Box 40, Folder *)
      See Oversize Material Box 2, Folder 5.
    - Robins, Edward death certificate, 1865 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Robins, Ephraim 1803-1842, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 11)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 5.
    - Robins, Ephraim--letters from John C. Calhoun 1824, 1846, 1824 -1826 (Box 40, Folder 12)